Chandler Brossard Papers
Chandler Brossard Papers
1951-2002
Brossard, Chandler, 1922-1993.
9 linear ft.
Papers of the American novelist, playwright, editor, and teacher. Correspondence and memorabilia as well as manuscripts, drafts, typescripts, and production material for Brossard's numerous novels, short stories, essays and plays. Correspondents include Alice Adams, Donald Allen, Malcolm Bradbury, Kent Carroll, Noam Chomsky, Wheeler Dixon, Guy Daniels, Joe Flaherty, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, John Clellon Holmes, Seymour Krim, James Laughlin, Ron Padgett, Charles Plymell, William Shawn, Gilbert Sorrentino, and others.
148869
Biographical History
Chandler Brossard (1922-1993) was an American novelist, playwright, editor, and teacher.
Born on July 18, 1922 in Idaho Falls, Idaho, he grew up in Washington, D.C. Brossard was chiefly self-educated, having left school at age eleven. He worked as a journalist for the Washington Post before attaining a writing position with The New Yorker at age nineteen, where editor William Shawn encouraged him to write fiction. His first published novel, Who Walk in Darkness (1952), focused on the bohemian life of 1940s Greenwich Village and is sometimes considered the first beat novel, thus earning Brossard an association with early Beat Generation writers such as Jack Kerouac and Allen Ginsberg -- an association Brossard neither sought nor desired. Reviewers who characterized Who Walk in Darkness as a beat novel, Brossard said, "totally missed getting the book. They thought it was a realistic novel, which of course it wasn't. The French critics knew better. They perceived it as the first 'new wave' novel, a nightmare presented as flat documentary." (Dictionary of Literary Biography, Volume 16: The Beats: Literary Bohemians in Postwar America, pp. 43-45.)
Brossard received little critical support for his novels in the United States (though they were well-received abroad, particularly in France). In 1971 Anatole Broyard wrote a scathing review of Wake Up. We're Almost There for the New York Times: "Here's a book so transcendently bad it makes us fear not only for the condition of the novel in this country, but for the country itself." Brossard responded in kind and a small controversy festered between them for a time. Two of Brossard's novels -- The Wrong Turn (Avon, 1954) and The Double View (Dial, 1960) -- were published under the pseudonym "Daniel Harper."
In addition to producing novels, plays and short stories, Brossard worked as an editor for Time magazine (1944), executive editor for American Mercury (1950-1951), and senior editor for Look magazine (1956-1967). He also wrote criticism for The Nation, Commentary, and The Guardian. From 1968-1970, he was a professor at the experimental Old Westbury College on Long Island and subsequently held brief teaching appointments as a visiting professor, writer-in-residence, or lecturer at universities in the United States and abroad, including the University of Birmingham in England, the New School for Social Research in New York, and Schiller College (now Schiller International University) in Paris.
Brossard was married twice and had three daughters. He died in 1993.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Chandler Brossard Papers contains the papers of the American novelist, playwright, editor, and teacher. Correspondence-subject files contains Brossard's correspondence with editors (Joyce Engelson, Daniel Halpern, Jay Landesman, Mark Zussman), publishers (Bobbs-Merrill Company, Daniel Cointe, Editions Gallimard, Fawcett, New Directions), writers (Noam Chomsky, E.L. Doctorow, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Peter Matthiessen, Marshall McLuhan), and family (daughters Geneve, Iris and Marie, mother Therese and brother Boyd). The literary spat between Brossard and critic Anatole Broyard is well documented.
Writings comprises typescripts, drafts, annotated drafts, manuscripts, notebooks, and other material related to Brossards novels, plays, essays, and short stories. Most strongly represented are the novels As the Wolf Howls at My Door (1992) and Wake Up. We’re Almost There (1971), with 18 and 20 folders respectively. This series also includes one unpublished novel entitled She Cried Out to Me. Memorabilia consists of publicity, reader's reports, and reviews.
Related Material
The also has a number of books by Brossard. Please refer to and search for Brossard, Chandler as author.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radicalism; Literature -- American Fiction; Adams, Alice, 1926-1999.; Allen, Donald Merriam, 1912-; Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1904-1985.; Brossard, Chandler, 1922-1993.; Brossard, Chandler, 1922-1993 -- Who walk in darkness.; Brossard, Chandler, 1922-1993 -- As the wolf howls at my door.; Brossard, Chandler, 1922-1993 -- Wake up. We're almost there.; Broyard, Anatole.; Chomsky, Noam.; Codrescu, Andrei, 1946-; Daniels, Guy.; Doctorow, E. L., 1931-; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence.; Friedman, Bruce Jay, 1930-; Hiss, Alger.; Holmes, John Clellon, 1926-1988.; Kees, Weldon, 1914-1955.; Krassner, Paul.; Krim, Seymour, 1922-; Landesman, Jay.; Mariah, Paul.; McLuhan, Marshall, 1911-1980.; Micheline, Jack, 1929-1998.; Padgett, Ron.; Plymell, Charles.; Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1905-1980.; Sontag, Susan, 1933-2004.; Sorrentino, Gilbert.; American literature -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; Bohemianism -- United States.; Bohemianism in literature.; Dramatists, American.; Literature, Experimental.; Novelists, American.; Articles.; Book reviews.; Correspondence.; Notebooks.; Galley proofs.; Scripts (documents); Authors.; Novelists.; Playwrights.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Chandler Brossard, 1970 et seq.
Inventory
- Biographical information
  - Interview, 1984; self-interview, in preparation for his contribution to Contemporary Authors Autobiography Series, Vol. 2 (Gale Research Company) (Oversize 1)
- Correspondence-subject files
  - A, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Adams, Alice, undated; includes postcards (Box 1)
  - Androla, Ron (poet), 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Appignanesi, Lisa, 1976 (Box 1)
    See also Writers and Readers Publishing Cooperative
  - Appignanesi, Richard, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Aronson, James (writer), 1973-1976 (Box 1)
  - Auw, Ivan von (agent), 1954-1955; 1968 (Box 1)
  - B, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Baizer, Eric (writer), 1977-1980; 1982,; undated (Box 1)
  - Belmont Productions, Inc. (publisher), 1963; 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Benedict, Elizabeth (writer), 1981 (Box 1)
  - Berger, John (writer), 1976 (Box 1)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Blackburn, Alexander, 1979; 1981 (Box 1)
  - The Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc. (publisher), 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Bowers, John (writer), 1986; undated (Box 1)
    See also The Review of Contemporary Fiction, Chandler Brossard issue (Vol. VII, no. 1)
  - Brooke-Rose, Christine (writer), 1974 (Box 1)
  - Brossard, Boyd (brother), undated (Box 1)
  - Brossard, Geneve (daughter), undated; includes handmade card and drawings (Box 1)
  - Brossard, Iris (daughter), 1984; 1988,; undated (Box 1)
  - Brossard, Marie (daughter), 1988 (Box 1)
  - Brossard, Therese (mother), undated (Box 1)
  - Broyard, Anatole, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Burchett, Wilfred, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Busch, Frederick, undated (Box 1)
  - C, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Calderone, Claudio (writer, United Nations official), 1981-1983; 1986-1988,; undated (Box 1)
  - Cetner, Marc (editor, National Enquirer), undated (Box 1)
  - Cherry Valley Editions (publisher), 1980-1981; 1984,; undated (Box 1)
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1970-1971; 1975-1977,; 1981,; 1986,; undated (Box 1)
  - City Lights (bookseller), 1977-1978; 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Codrescu, Andrei, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Cointe, Daniel (publisher of Dirty Books for Little Folks), 1977-1980; 1984-1986,; undated (Box 1)
  - Coleman, Lonnie, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Compendium Bookshop (London), 1977; 1984-1985,; undated (Box 1)
  - Corwin, Phillip, 1971; includes correspondence regarding Anatole Broyard’s review of Brossard's Wake Up. We’re Almost There (Box 1)
  - Coyne, John (writer, director of admissions at Old Westbury), 1969; 1971,; 1982,; 1985,; undated (Box 1)
  - D, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - d'Heurle, Francois (scientist for IBM), 1971; letter to the editor published in the New York Times Book Review regarding Anatole Broyard’s review of Brossard's Wake Up. We’re Almost There (Box 1)
  - Doctorow, E.L., 1977 (Box 1)
  - Donadio, Candida (agent), 1963-1964; undated (Box 1)
  - Duer, David (publisher), 1984; undated (Box 1)
  - E, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Editions Gallimard (publisher, Paris, France), 1968; 1970,; 1984-1986,; undated (Box 1)
  - Engelson, Joyce (editor), 1970; 1977-1978,; 1981,; undated (Box 1)
  - F, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Fawcett Publications, Inc., 1959; 1962,; 1964-1966,; 1968,; undated (Box 1)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Fisher, M.F.K., 1986 (Box 1)
  - Flam, Jack (art professor/historian, writer), 1975-1979; 1981-1982,; 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Friedenberg, Edgar Zodiag (writer), 1968; 1974-1975,; 1977,; 1981,; 1986,; undated (Box 1)
  - Friedman, Bruce Jay, 1963; undated (Box 1)
  - Frommer, Arthur (publisher), 1963; undated (Box 1)
  - G, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Gale Research Company (publisher), 1984-1985; includes correspondence related to CB’s contribution to the Contemporary Authors Autobiography Series (Box 1)
    See also Biographical information: Interview
  - Garrison, Jim (district attorney), 1969; 1971 (Box 1)
  - Geis, Bernard (publisher), 1963 (Box 1)
  - Goldberg, Harry (head of American Library in Paris), 1979-1980; 1982,; 1984-1989,; undated (Box 2)
  - Gordon, Selma (children’s book author), 1981-1982; 1984 (Box 2)
  - H, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Haigh, Isabel (Mrs. Richard), undated (Box 2)
  - Haigh, Richard (historian), undated (Box 2)
  - Halpern, Daniel (poet, editor for Antaeus, 1977; undated (Box 2)
  - Harper's Magazine, 1971-1974; 1976-1979,; 1984 (Box 2)
  - Harrison, William (writer), 1977 (Box 2)
  - Hentoff, Nat, 1971; note referring to Anatole Broyard’s review of Brossard's Wake Up. We’re Almost There (Box 2)
  - Hiss, Alger, undated (Box 2)
  - Holland-Skinner, Con (writer), 1984; 1987 (Box 2)
  - Holmes, John Clellan, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - Huffman, Grace (mother-in-law; mother to actress Felicity Huffman), 1983; 1985,; 1986-1987,; undated (Box 2)
  - Huffman, Maria (second wife; mother to Geneve), undated (Box 2)
  - I, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - J, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Jonk, Clarence (writer), 1981 (Box 2)
  - K, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Kearney, Michael (anthropologist, writer), 1977-1985 (Box 2)
  - Kees, Weldon, 1955 (Box 2)
    See also Reidel, James
  - Kinnell, Galway, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Kolokithas, Dawn (writer, poet, editor for Pacific Poetry & Fiction Review), 1980 (Box 2)
  - Krassner, Paul (writer, founder/editor of The Realist), 1972 (Box 2)
  - Krim, Seymour (writer, editor), 1962; 1968,; 1981-1982,; 1984-1985,; undated (Box 2)
  - L, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Land, Myrick (writer), 1983 (Box 2)
  - Landesman, Jay (writer, editor, publisher), 1955; 1969-1970,; 1972-1974,; 1977-1978,; 1980-1981,; 1983-1988,; undated (Box 2)
  - Lange, Monique (writer, screenwriter, editor), 1970 (Box 2)
  - Lapham, Lewis H. (editor, Harper’s Magazine), 1971-1974; 1976-1979,; 1984 (Box 2)
  - Lawrence, Kathleen Rockwell (writer), 1987 (Box 2)
  - Lemmon, Jack (actor), 1968; letter regarding article CB wrote about Lemmon for Look (Box 2)
  - Levy, William (writer), 1984; 1986-1987,; undated (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Anthony (writer, journalist), 1973 (Box 2)
  - Lowry, Robert, 1977; 1979,; 1987; includes introductory sheet from Lowry’s workshop at Writer’s Digest School, with photograph of Lowry (photocopy) (Box 2)
  - Lykiard, Alexis (poet, writer), 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Lykiard, Erika (Mrs. Alexis), 1986-1988; undated (Box 2)
  - M, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Mariah, Paul (poet, writer), 1977 (Box 2)
  - Matthiessen, Peter (writer), 1962; undated (Box 2)
  - McLuhan, Marshall (writer), 1955 (Box 2)
  - Mehta, Sonny (a.k.a. Ajai Singh, publisher, editor-in-chief at Alfred A. Knopf), 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Micheline, Jack, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Miller, Stuart (writer), 1968; 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Moore, David (publisher), 1980; 1984-1987,; 1989 (Box 2)
  - Moore, Steven (writer, bibliographer), 1983-1989; undated (Box 2)
  - N, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - New Directions (publisher), 1951-1952; 1955,; 1962-1963,; 1971,; 1980,; 1982-1983,; undated (Box 2)
  - O, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - O’Brien, John, See The Review of Contemporary Fiction
  - Old Westbury, See State University of New York - College at Old Westbury
  - P, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Padgett, Ron (poet, publisher), 1982 (Box 2)
  - Pantucci, Gabriele (agent), 1974-1976; 1978 (Box 2)
  - Peabody, Richard (editor, writer), 1979-1981; 1983-1985,; undated (Box 2)
  - Phoenix Book Shop (seller of CB’s manuscript archive), 1972; 1977,; 1983,; 1985 (Box 2)
  - Plymell, Charles (writer, poet, publisher), 1980; 1984 (Box 2)
  - The Poetry Center (92nd St. Y), 1982 (Box 2)
  - Poets & Writers, 1975-1978; 1980,; 1982,; 1984,; undated (Box 3)
  - Porter, Cathy (writer), undated (Box 3)
  - Protter, Eric (editor, writer, publisher), 1973; 1975,; undated (Box 3)
  - Protter, Susan Ann (agent), 1979; 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Pryor, Roberta (agent), 1966-1968; undated (Box 3)
  - Quattrocchi, Angelo (writer), undated (Box 3)
  - R, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Ramnath, S. (writer, editor), 1984 (Box 3)
  - Reidel, James (writer), 1984 (Box 3)
  - The Review of Contemporary Fiction, Chandler Brossard issue (Vol. VII, no. 1), 1980; 1983-1986; special issue focusing on Brossard and his work, edited and published by John O’Brien (Box 3)
    See also individual contributors by name.
  - Riesman, David (sociologist, educator), 1968-1970 (Box 3)
  - Rinehart and Company (publisher), 1954-1956; undated (Box 3)
  - Rosten, Norman (writer), 1968 (Box 3)
  - S, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Salter, James (writer), undated (Box 3)
  - Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1967; letter to Mme. Simonne Gauthier-Finnbogason referencing CB (Box 3)
  - Schneck, Stephen (writer), 1973 (Box 3)
  - Serendipity Books, 1980; 1983; bookseller involved with selling CB’s manuscript archive, includes detailed description of archive entitled "Chandler Brossard Manuscripts" (Box 3)
  - Sherman, Lonnie (writer), 1984; undated (Box 3)
  - Silber, Irwin (editor), 1969 (Box 3)
  - The Smith, 1974; 1977,; undated (Box 3)
  - Solomon, Barbara Probst (writer, contributor to Review of Contemporary Fiction, Chandler Brossard issue), undated (Box 3)
  - Sontag, Susan, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Soos, Richard A. (publisher, writer), undated (Box 3)
  - Sorrentino, Gilbert, 1977; 1981 (Box 3)
  - State University of New York - College at Old Westbury, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
    See also Coyne, John
  - Student correspondence, 1969; in support of CB’s tenure at Old Westbury (Box 3)
  - Subraman, Belinda (Mary) (writer, poet, editor, publisher), 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Sutton, Eileen, 1988 (Box 3)
  - T, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Talbot, Daniel (editor), undated (Box 3)
  - Tennant, Emma (writer, editor), undated (Box 3)
  - Tipton, David (publisher), 1985-1988; undated; includes correspondence related to publishing CB’s Postcards and Closing the Gap (Box 3)
  - Tran, Van Dinh (writer, teacher), 1967-1970 (Box 3)
  - True, 1970-1971; includes correspondence regarding CB’s so-called "CIA piece" (Box 3)
  - U, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - V, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Vachon, John (photographer), undated (Box 3)
  - Van Arkadie, Elaine, undated (Box 3)
  - The Village Voice, 1973-1974; 1977,; 1983,; undated (Box 3)
  - W, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Wetzsteon, Ross (writer, editor), 1973-1974; undated (Box 3)
  - Wilcock, John (writer), 1972; undated (Box 3)
  - Wilke, Susan (painter), 1984-1988 (Box 3)
  - William Morris Agency (agent Don Gold and others), 1968-1973; undated (Box 3)
  - Writers and Readers Publishing Cooperative, 1976 (Box 3)
    See also Appignanesi, Lisa and Appignanesi, Richard
  - Y, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Yaddo (artists’ community, Saratoga Springs, New York), 1981; 1987 (Box 3)
  - Young, Al (writer, poet, editor), 1997 (Box 3)
  - Zussman, Mark (editor, Oui), 1974-1976; undated (Box 3)
  - Unidentified correspondence, 1 folder (Box 3)
- Writings
  - Books
    - As the Wolf Howls at My Door (Dalkey Archive), 1992; working titles: Somebody’s Been Sleeping in My Bed; Somebody’s Been Eating My Porridge; Thin Air; Come Out with Your Hands Up
      - 9 notebooks, 7 folders (Box 4)
      - Draft annotated typescript, 5 folders (Box 4, 5)
      - Typescript, 6 folders (Box 5, 6)
    - The Bold Saboteurs (Dell), 1953; Excerpts - draft typescripts, some annotated; 8 folders (Box 6)
    - A Chimney Sweep Comes Clean (Realities Library), 1985; working title: Confessions of a Chimney Sweep; notebook; draft annotated typescript; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Closing the Gap (Redbeck Press), 1986; notes - 1 small notebook; draft, 2 notebooks; ms; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Dirty Books for Little Folks (Daniel Cointe), 1978; working title: Smut for Small Fry
      - Notebook (Box 6)
      - "Jack and the Beanstalk", draft, annotated typescript (Box 6)
      - "Little Red Riding Hood: Three Quite New Versions", draft, annotated typescript; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - The Double View (Dial Press), 1960; corrected typescript; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - The Insane World of Adolf Hitler (Fawcett Publications), 1966
      - Corrected typescript (Box 7)
      - Production records – photo layouts (Oversize 1)
    - A Man for All Women (Fawcett Publications), 1966; corrected typescript; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Postcards: Don’t You Just Wish You Were Here? (Redbeck Press), 1987; notebook, ms; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - She Cried Out to Me (unpublished novel), undated; Draft annotated typescript (Box 7)
    - The Spanish Scene (Viking Press), 1968
      - Notes – 1 small notebook (Box 7)
      - Corrected typescript, 2 folders (Box 7, 8)
      - Layouts (Box 8)
      - Author’s corrected galley proofs (Box 8)
      - Duplicate page proof (Box 8)
    - Wake Up. We’re Almost There (R.W. Baron), 1971
      - Notebooks, 8 folders (Box 8, 9)
      - Excerpt – annotated typescript, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Draft – retypes and inserts (Box 9)
      - Setting copy, 5 folders (Box 9, 10)
      - Corrected page proofs (Box 10)
      - Uncorrected page proofs (Box 11)
      - Production records - Layouts (Oversize 1)
      - Cover artwork (Box 11)
    - Who Walk in Darkness (New Directions), 1952; annotated typescript; setting copy; 5 folders (Box 11)
    - The Wolf Leaps: Did Christ Make Love? (Herodias), 2002; originally published as Did Christ Make Love? by Bobbs-Merrill, 1973; typescript titled The Wolf Leaps (Box 12)
  - Essays
    - "About Wake Up", typescript (Box 12)
    - "The Child’s Style of Learning", printed material (Box 12)
    - "The Culture of Violence", photocopied draft (Box 12)
    - "The Fiction Scene: or Has Anybody Seen Billy Goat Gruff Lately?", draft annotated typescript; corrected galley proofs; setting copy; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - "How We Lie to Our Children", photocopied draft (Box 12)
    - "Letter Found Inside an Aztec Washed Up on the Steps to the Temple", typescript (Box 12)
    - "Making Life Tougher", printed material (Box 12)
    - "The Menorcan Papers: History as Language and Human Garbage", outline, annotated typescript; draft annotated typescript; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Introduction to Neurotica, draft annotated typescript (Box 12)
    - "Non-Happenings in Change", typescript (Box 12)
    - "North Toward Home", review, typescript (Box 12)
    - "Old Westbury College: A Fraud Revisited", draft annotated typescript (Box 12)
    - "The Ritual of Originality", printed material (Box 12)
    - "Tentative Visits to the Cemetery: Reflections on My Beat Generation", draft; corrected typescript; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - "Whatever Became of Fiction?", draft typescript (Box 12)
  - Scripts
    - Catch as Catch Can: A Comedy (Box 12)
    - Love's Success (Box 12)
    - The Man with Ideas: A Comedy, draft typescript (Box 13)
    - Some Dreams Aren’t Real: A Comedy, annotated typescript (Box 13)
    - Tish and Judy, draft, 2 notebooks; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - The True Test of Friendship, Draft, notebook; typescript; photocopy; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Up and At Them: A Comedy (Box 13)
    - Untitled fragment, typescript (Box 13)
  - Stories
    - "Afterward", typescript (Box 13)
    - "At the Fights", typescript (Box 13)
    - "Bachelor’s Room", typescript (Box 13)
    - "The Big Meet", typescript (Box 13)
    - "Billy and the Boys", typescript (Box 13)
    - "Un Buon Café", typescript (Box 13)
    - "The Castle At Last", typescript (photocopy) (Box 13)
    - "The Color of Fall", typescript; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - "Drowning Grass", annotated typescript, typescript; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - "Games on the Beach", typescript (Box 13)
    - "The Green Cadillac", typescript; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - "In Florence", See "Remembrance of Italy"
    - "Interview in the Morning", annotated typescript (Box 13)
      See also A Man for All Women
    - "An Italian Story", See "Remembrance of Italy"
    - "Italy, 1947-48", See "Remembrance of Italy"
    - "Letter from the Conscious to the Unconscious", annotated typescript (Box 13)
      See also The Bold Saboteurs (excerpt VI)
    - "The Lido", typescript; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - "The Little Boy Who Wanted to Be Somebody Else", typescript (Box 14)
    - "Love under the Arcades", annotated typescript, typescript; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - "The Major’s Return", See "Remembrance of Italy"
    - "Mascara", typescript (Box 14)
    - "A New World for Deborah", typescript (entitled "Penny’s New World"), printed material; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - "One if for Sorrow, Two if for Joy", annotated typescript, typescript; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - "Ouch! And Oh! (And All That)", annotated galley proof (Box 14)
    - "The Plan", annotated typescript (Box 14)
    - "Playground", typescript (Box 14)
    - "Portrait", typescript (Box 14)
    - "Reluctant Ally", typescript (Box 14)
    - "Remembrance of Italy", Part I:"Where One Goes"; Part II: "The Major’s Return"; Part III: "In Florence"
      - Annotated typescript (Box 14)
      - Typescript entitled "An Italian Story" (Box 14)
      - Typescript entitled "Italy 1947-48" (Box 14)
      - Typescript entitled "The Major’s Return" (Box 14)
      - Printed material, published as "The Way It Was in Italy" (Box 14)
      - Typescript entitled "In Florence" (Box 14)
    - "The Right Direction", annotated typescript, typescript; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - "The Robber Next Door", typescript (entitled "Robbery in the Suburbs), annotated typescript; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - "A Sense of Relief", typescript (Box 14)
    - "Some Other Way", annotated typescript, typescript; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - "The Stolen Ride", typescript; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - "The Strange Pick-Up", annotated typescript (Box 14)
    - "Sunday Revelation", typescript (Box 14)
    - "Vacation for Three", annotated typescript (Box 14)
    - "A Very Nice Place", printed material (Box 14)
    - "A Very Strange Bet", typescript (Box 14)
    - "Voyage", typescript (Box 14)
    - "The Way It Was", typescript (Box 14)
    - "The Way It Was in Italy", See "Remembrance of Italy"
    - "Where One Goes", See "Remembrance of Italy"
    - "Who Walk In Darkness", annotated typescript; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Miscellany, untitled fragment typescript; unidentified manuscript pages typescript, printed material; 7 notebooks; 5 folders (Box 14, 15)
- Memorabilia
  - Publicity
    - Dirty Books for Little Folks, advertisement/order form (Box 15)
    - Love's Success, announcement of production opening (Box 15)
  - Reports
    - Reader’s reports, typescript (Box 15)
  - Reviews